Todd Johnson

Machine operator, product inspector and packager

Evansville, IN 47714 tjdadon041@gmail.com 812-205-6545

Highly motivated with four years of military skills and experience. A reliable and responsible worker who gets the task done at hand quickly and efficiently. Good at communicating and working with others. A honest, positive, and dedicated worker who is focused on applying four years of military skills and experience to any job that I am tasked with, and towards goals. Calm under pressure with superior time management and conflict resolution skills. Thinks carefully before acting, able to adapt to any work environment, learns tremendously from mistakes, and increases the morale of fellow employees.

Work Experience

Machine operator, product inspector and packager

Berry Plastics

July 2017 to November 2017

Fisher Dynamics, 11/13/2017-Currrent

- Production and Assembly
- Machine Operator
- Plex computer system operator

United States Postal Service - Evansville, IN March 2015 to February 2017

- Unload, process, sort, and distribute US and foreign mail, small letters and large packages.
- Use large conveyors to lift mail containers onto conveyor belt to be scanned and organized by country, state, city, and zip code.
- Used fork trucks to load and unload mail from postal delivery trucks.

Ticketing and Packaging - Evansville, IN February 2013 to April 2013

- Loaded and unloaded pieces into boxes for shipment.
- Moved freight, stock, and other materials to and from storage and production areas and loading docks.
- Received, stored, and shipped goods and materials.
- Tagged all inbound merchandise with receiving date.
- Cleaned and maintained the warehouse in compliance with OSHA safety standards.
- Tracked time spent on assignments each day for productivity reporting.
- Stacked and stored pallets at the end of the shift to keep warehouse clean and organized.
- Swept floors and stored equipment at the end of each shift.
- Recorded numbers of units handled and moved using daily production sheets and work tickets.
- Attached identifying tags to containers.

Security Sentry - Naval Station Everett, WA January 2010 to August 2011

- Performed as a fire team member during situational training exercises and all infantry dismounted drills.
- Communicated urgent orders and directions effectively to team members.
- Assisted in security force protection programs to meet fleet requirements.
- Maintained internal security of Naval base and within Naval carrier ship.
- Maintained order and security in private areas of the ship and base.

Supervisor

Food Service - Naval Station Everett, WA July 2009 to December 2009

- Trained kitchen/galley personnel to ensure smooth adoption of new food preparation methods.
- Demonstrated integrity and honesty while interacting with fellow sailors and team members.
- Greeted fellow sailors and provided excellent customer service.
- Maintained high standards of customer service during high-volume, fast-paced operations.
- Followed food safety procedures according to company policies and health and sanitation regulations.
- Reported to all shifts wearing a neat, clean, and unwrinkled uniform.
- Reported to each shift on time and ready to work.
- Performed all position responsibilities accurately and in a timely manner.
- Communicated openly and honestly with fellow team members team during each shift to ensure it ran

smoothly.

- In charge of organizing and leading a team of over fifteen people.
- Managed kitchen/galley personnel by orienting, training, supervising, and enforcing kitchen/galley rules.
- Instructed new staff in proper food preparation, food storage, and use of kitchen equipment and utensils, sanitation and safety issues.
- Led shifts while personally preparing food items.

worker

Food Service - Naval Station Everett, WA August 2007 to June 2009

Prepared food items consistently and in compliance with recipes, portioning, cooking and waste control

guidelines.

- Verified proper portion sizes and consistently maintained high food quality standards..
- Maintained smooth and timely operations in preparation and delivery of meals and kitchen sanitation.
- Properly labeled and stored all raw food ingredients including produce, meat, fish, poultry, dairy and dry goods in the appropriate storage room, walk-in refrigerator, freezer or cooler.

Food Service and Custodian

Tampa International Airport - Tampa, FL March 2006 to August 2007

- Refilled and rotated items on shelves to maintain well-stocked inventory.
- Scanned shelves and product cases for expired stock and discarded outdated or spoiled items.
- Cleaned food shelves, storage area and work areas and kept floors free of spills, water and hazardous debris.

- Monitored temperature of cases, shelves and storage areas and reported failures to the manager.
- Followed proper standards for product freshness, food safety, weights and measures, refrigeration and sanitation.
- Developed knowledge about products and sales items to answer shoppers' questions.
- Packaged and labeled products.
- 1 year of custodial work.

Education

Associate of Arts in Psychology

University of Phoenix - Phoenix, AZ 2013

Bachelors of Science in Communication

University of Phoenix - Phoenix, AZ

Skills

MICROSOFT WORD, WORD

Additional Information

Skills

- * Self-motivated
- * Strong verbal communication
- * Conflict resolution
- * Organized
- * Strong work ethic
- * Won't guit till the job is completed
- * Great listening skills
- * Follow directions well
- * Always on time for work
- * Computer proficient
- * Good communication skills
- * Microsoft Word knowledge
- * Work well within a team.
- * Capable of getting the job done efficiently and effectively with little to no supervision.
- * Can carry my own weight or workload
- * Desire to excel
- * Ability to adapt
- * Can work in slow or fast paced environments
- * Critical thinking skills
- * Wiliness to help others if my job is done
- * Quick learner
- * Great at multi-tasking

* Able to meet goals and consistent at meeting goals